const questions = [
    {
        question: "The three basic components of an atom are?",
        a: "Protons, neutrons, and ions",
        b: "Protons, neutrons, and electrons",
        c: "Protons, neutrinos, and ions",
        d: "Protium, deuterium, and tritium",
        answer: "B",
        explanation: `<p>Although they can be broken further into subatomic particles, the three main components of 
        an atom are protons, neutrons, and electrons. In order to be considered an atom, there needs to be at least 
        a single proton (which is the most common form of hydrogen).</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "An element is determined by the number of?",
        a: "Atoms",
        b: "Electrons",
        c: "Neutrons",
        d: "Protons",
        answer: "D",
        explanation: `<p>Back in Mendeleev's time, before scientists knew about the parts of the atom, each element 
        was recognized by its atom's atomic weight. In modern times, we identify atoms based on how many protons they 
        contain.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "The nucleus of an atom consists of?",
        a: "Electrons",
        b: "Neutrons",
        c: "Protons and neutrons",
        d: "Protons, neutrons, and electrons",
        answer: "C",
        explanation: `<p>The core of an atom is its nucleus, which consists of protons and neutrons that stick to each 
        other because of the strong nuclear force.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "A single proton has what electrical charge?",
        a: "No charge",
        b: "Positive charge",
        c: "Negative charge",
        d: "Either a positive or negative charge",
        answer: "B",
        explanation: `<p>A proton has a +1 electrical charge. An electron has a -1 electrical charge. Neutrons are 
        electrical neutral, which means they have no net electrical charge.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "Which particles have approximately the same size and mass as each other?",
        a: "Neutrons and electrons",
        b: "Electrons and protons",
        c: "Protons and neutrons",
        d: "None - all are different in terms of size and mass",
        answer: "C",
        explanation: `<p>Protons and neutrons have nearly the same size and mass. Electrons are so much smaller and 
        lighter they basically don't even affect the mass of an atom.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "Which two particles would be attracted to each other?",
        a: "Electrons and neutrons",
        b: "Electrons and protons",
        c: "Protons and neutrons",
        d: "All particles are attracted to each other",
        answer: "B",
        explanation: `<p>Opposites attract, at least when they have opposite electrical charges. So, protons and 
        electrons are attracted to each other. Protons repel other protons. Electrons repel other electrons. Neutrons 
        are neither attracted to nor repelled by other particles.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "The atomic number of an atom is",
        a: "The number of electrons",
        b: "The number of neutrons",
        c: "The number of protons",
        d: "The number of protons plus the number of neutrons",
        answer: "C",
        explanation: `<p>The atomic number of an atom is the same as the number of protons it has. For example, 
        hydrogen has one proton and is atomic number 1. Each helium atom has two protons, so the element is atomic 
        number 2. Simple, right?</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "Changing the number of neutrons of an atom changes its?",
        a: "Isotope",
        b: "Element",
        c: "Ion",
        d: "Charge",
        answer: "A",
        explanation: `<p>Atoms that have the same number of protons, but different numbers of neutrons from each 
        other are called isotopes of that element.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "When you change the number of electrons on an atom, you produce a different?",
        a: "Isotope",
        b: "Element",
        c: "Ion",
        d: "Atomic mass",
        answer: "C",
        explanation: `<p> If you have a different number of protons and electrons in an atom, it is an ion. If there 
        are more electrons, the ion has a net negative electrical charge and is called an anion. If there are fewer 
        electrons than protons, the ion has a net positive electrical charge and is called a cation.</p>`,
    },
    {
        question: "According to atomic theory, electrons are usually found?",
        a: "In the atomic nucleus",
        b: "Outside the nucleus, yet very near it because they are attracted to protons",
        c: "Outside the nucleus -- most of an atom's volume is the electron cloud",
        d: "Anywhere they want to be -- no particular location is more likely than any other",
        answer: "C",
        explanation: `<p>It's theoretically possible to find an electron anywhere, but it's most probable any given 
        electron orbits in its electron shell. The electron shells are far away from the nucleus, sort of like how 
        the planets orbit far from the Sun.</p>`,
    },
];
